heliumnetwork.com 2019-05-30

# Editorial Opportunities, Online Publisher: Privacy Policy | Helium Network

## Helium is Committed to Your Right to Privacy

Helium, Inc., a subsidiary of RR Donnelley & Sons Company (“Helium,” “we”, “our”) is committed to protecting your privacy. By using this website (“Site”) and by supplying your details to Helium, you consent to Helium collecting and processing your information.

Our privacy policy explains:

  * What information we collect, and why we collect it
  * How we use that information
  * How we protect that information
  * How you can control your information, including accessing, updating and deleting what we store
  * How we share information collected

**Information We Collect & Share**

Helium collects and records basic personal information (e.g., name, e-mail address, mailing address, phone number) which you voluntarily provide through forms on our Site, through electronic mail you send to us, or through other means of communication between you and Helium. Once you register with Helium and sign into our services, you are not anonymous to us. Helium only collects personal information of a more sensitive nature (e.g. social security or tax ID number) where it is appropriate or necessary for conducting business. This information will be collected, stored, accessed and processed in a secure manner. Helium automatically receives and records information on our server logs from your browser, including your IP address, Helium cookie information (if any), and the page you request.

**How We Use Information**

Helium uses information for the following general purposes: to fulfill your requests for products and services, to customize the content and advertising you see, to improve our services, to contact you, to conduct research, to process payments and to provide anonymous reporting for internal and external clients. Helium uses the information we collect to provide you with services that you request and to improve our existing services and the content of our Site. When you contact Helium, we may keep a record of your communication to help solve any issues that you are facing. Depending on the country in which you live, work or access our Site(s), your information may be retained for a reasonable time for use in future contact with you, or for future improvements to the Helium Site.

**Web User Tracking – Use of Cookies**

Cookies are a technology that can be used to help personalize your use of a website. A cookie is an element of information that a website can send to your browser, which may then store it on your system. You can set your browser to notify you when you receive a cookie, giving you the chance to decide whether to accept it or decline at any time. To enable Helium to access the effectiveness and usefulness of this Site, and to give you the best user experience, we collect and store information on pages viewed by you, your domain names and similar information. No other web sites can access cookies set by Helium, nor can the Helium Sites access cookies set by other websites.  Our Site makes use of anonymous cookies for the purposes of:

  * Completion and support of Site activity;
  * Site and system administration;
  * Research and development;
  * Anonymous user analysis, user profiling, and decision-making.

**Security**

The security of your personal information is important to us. We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it.

Helium limits access to personal information about you to employees who we believe reasonably need to come into contact with that information to provide products or services to you or in order to do their jobs. We have physical, electronic and procedural safeguards that comply with federal regulations to protect personal information about you. Your Helium Account Information is password-protected. In certain areas, Helium uses industry-standard SSL encryption to protect data transmissions.

Data you provide to us will be stored on our servers located in the United States. By providing us with your information, you understand and consent to the international transfer of your data to the United States.

No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, can be 100% secure. Therefore, Helium cannot guarantee the absolute security of your information. The Internet by its nature is a public forum, and Helium encourages you to use caution when disclosing information online. Often, you are in the best situation to protect yourself online. You are responsible for protecting your username and password from third party access, and for selecting passwords that are secure.

**Monitoring and Enforcement**

Helium regularly reviews our compliance with our privacy policy. We also adhere to several self-regulatory frameworks in addition to complying with applicable law. If we receive formal written complaints, we will follow up with the person making the complaint. We work with the appropriate regulatory authorities to resolve any complaints that cannot be resolved directly.

**Compliance**

Helium adheres to applicable US federal and state personal information privacy laws and international regulations such as PIPEDA, the European Union (“EU”) Data Protection (95/46/EC) and ePrivacy (2002/58/ED) Directives (as transposed into national law), and the EU Safe Harbor Privacy Principles published by the US Department of Commerce (“Safe Harbor”), detailed below.

**PIPEDA (Canada)**

Helium recognizes and has controls in place to ensure that the privacy of personal information about an “identifiable individual” used in the course of “commercial activity” is protected and managed in such a manner which meets or exceeds the guidelines set out in PIPEDA and applicable provincial legislation.

**Safe Harbor (European Union)**

Through your use of this system, you acknowledge that you are transmitting your information to systems housed in the United States.

As a subsidiary of RR Donnelley, Helium recognizes that the EU has an “omnibus” information protection regime established pursuant to the European Data Protection Directive (95/46/EC) (the “Directive”).  RR Donnelley has signed up to the US Department of Commerce’s Safe Harbor program and gives “adequate protection” for personal information of EU citizens processed and stored in the United States.   RR Donnelley takes appropriate technical and organizational measures to safeguard EU Personal Information against unauthorized or unlawful processing of, or accidental loss, damage, misuse, unauthorized access, unauthorized disclosure, unauthorized alteration, or destruction, and maintains reasonable procedures to help ensure that such information is relevant for its intended use, accurate, complete, current and not excessive and that such information is not retained longer than is reasonably necessary.

RR Donnelley may disclose EU Personal Information as necessary in connection with the sale or transfer of all or part of its business, where required or permitted by law, where RR Donnelley believes that such disclosures are appropriate in connection with a law enforcement request or as otherwise permitted by Safe Harbor, or in order to investigate, prevent or take action regarding illegal activities or suspected fraud or in order to comply with, enforce or apply RR Donnelley agreements.

For more information about the Safe Harbor program and RR Donnelley’s certification, please refer to the U.S. Department of Commerce website at [http://www.export.gov/safeharbor](http://www.export.gov/safeharbor).

**Links and Third-Party Ads**

We may post links to other web sites as a service to you. These sites are operated by companies that are outside of our control, and your activities at those sites will be governed by the policies and practices of those third parties.

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our Site. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other web sites in order to provide advertisements on this Site, other Sites and other forms of media about goods and services that may be of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, please visit [www.networkadvertising.org/choices](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices).

The advertising we display may be targeted to users of particular services and content. So if you view or click on a targeted ad, the advertiser (or other companies affiliated with the advertiser) may assume that you meet the targeting criteria (e.g., men aged 30-40).

**Children’s Online Privacy Protection – COPPA**

Helium is designed for adult user interaction. We do not intentionally collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of 13, nor do we allow children under age 13 to register for an account. If you are a parent and suspect that your child has provided Helium with any information, please contact us by email at help@helium.com.

**Accessing and Updating Your Personal Information**

If you have provided Helium with your personal information, you may have the right to inspect the information stored by us for accuracy. You can edit your Helium Account Information at any time by logging into the Site and entering the My Helium area. You may opt out of receiving Helium emails by clicking on the “Unsubscribe” link. Please note that even if you do opt out of receiving marketing materials, we reserve the right, and will continue to send you certain infrequent communications relating to the Helium service and/or your Account, such as service announcements and administrative messages, that are considered part of your Helium Account, without offering you the opportunity to opt out of receiving them.

**Changes to this Privacy Policy**

Helium may change this privacy policy from time to time. If this privacy policy changes, the revised privacy policy will be posted at the “Privacy Policy” link on the Site’s home page. In the event that the change is significant or material, we will notify you of such a change by posting a notice on the Helium Network dashboard and on the Helium Network homepage. Please check the privacy policy frequently. Your continued use of the Site constitutes acceptance of such changes in the privacy policy, except where further steps are required by applicable law.

**Contacting Helium**

Questions or comments regarding this privacy policy should be emailed to [help@heliumnetwork.com](mailto:help@heliumnetwork.com)

This privacy policy was last updated October 3, 2013.
